Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Benson Bond Moore papers
1902-1995
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Moore, Benson Bond
5.7 linear feet
The papers of printmaker and landscape painter Benson Bond Moore date from 1902 to 1995 and measure 5.7 linear feet. Found within the papers are biographical material, letters, scattered personal business records, notes and writings, twelve scrapbooks, printed material, and photographs. The papers also contain extensive artwork in the form of drawings and sketches, etchings, lithographs, and a few oil paintings.
Provenance
The Benson Bond Moore papers were donated by Barbara Nikla and John J. Lyons in 1996, as representatives of the estate of the artist's sister-in-law, Mary Jane Moore. Additional material was donated 1997 from the estate by other relatives, Martha Sigmon and her sister Georgia King.
Separated Material
Printmaking tools, lithographic plates, and a 24 x 30 inch display board exhibiting specimen prints and plates and a pocket barometer were transferred to the National Museum of American History, Department of Information Technology and Society.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Benson Bond Moore (1882-1974) of Washington, D.C. and Sarasota, Florida, was a printmaker, landscape painter, art teacher, and picture restorer.
Benson Bond Moore was born on August 13, 1882 in Washington, D.C., the first child of Caroline and John Benson Moore. From an early age, Moore assisted his father in his picture restoring business. In 1902, he was employed by the Maurice Joyce Photo-Engraving Co., and soon afterwards produced a series of technical drawings for Alexander Graham Bell.
Moore studied at the Corcoran School of Art, and, in 1914, he joined The Ramblers (later the Washington Landscape Club), a group of artists who went on painting and drawing expeditions in the environs of Washington, D.C. Moore taught etching at the private Hill School of Art and was an active member of many regional art associations. He was also a founding member of the Miniature Painters, Sculptors and Gravers Society. Following the death of his wife Florence (Flossie) in the early 1950s, Moore moved to Sarasota, Florida.
Benson Bond Moore died on October 30, 1974 in Sarasota, Florida.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of printmaker and landscape painter Benson Bond Moore date from 1902 to 1995 and measure 5.7 linear feet. Found within the papers are biographical material, letters, scattered personal business records, notes and writings, twelve scrapbooks, printed material, and photographs. The papers also contain extensive artwork in the form of drawings and sketches, etchings, lithographs, and a few oil paintings.
Biographical material includes genealogical notes, biographical accounts, a baptismal record, marriage license, driver's license, membership cards, an award medal and ribbons, a death certificate, and address books.
Letters are incoming only from friends and colleagues, including Christmas cards from Clifford K. Berryman, Paul Bransom, James Russell Lowe, Rowland Lyon, and Francis Bowes Sayre. There is also a photocopy of a letter from Lou Henry Hoover.
Personal business records include a copy of a patent for Moore's design for an artist's kit, a deed for Moore's father's gallery, priced labels for art work in various media, lists of art work, price lists, records of art work sold, bank account records, miscellaneous receipts, and a ledger concerning Moore's works left in trust after his death.
Notes and writings consist of nine poems by Moore, lists of titles of art work sold, lists of art work by others, and a funeral registry book listing mourners' names. The most notable item in this series is a log book of The Ramblers containing a typescript describing the history of this early 20th century art club.
Art work comprises the most significant series in the collection. It includes 1040 drawings, 43 watercolor sketches, 526 etchings, 187 lithographs, 8 paintings and 5 relief sculptures. Subjects depicted are primarily wildlife and nature, landscapes, seascapes, and scenes of towns and notable buildings primarily in and around Washington, D.C. There are scattered portrait drawings and etchings by Moore of fellow artists Herbert F. Clark, Robert G. Cornett, August H. O. Rolle, and Charles Seaton. There are also 5 bas-relief sculptures.
Twelve scrapbooks contain prints by Moore, letters, printed materials, and photographs of Moore and his artwork. Scrapbook 10 contains a photograph of a Landscape Club banquet at the Cosmos Club.
Printed material consists of clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, a prospectus from the Society of Animal Artists, book Animals of American History illustrated by Paul Bransom, miscellaneous booklets and brochures concerning art-related topics, travel brochures for New York State, and reproductions of art works.
Photographs are of Benson Bond Moore, his family, residence, colleagues including members of The Ramblers painting outdoors, and of art work. There are also travel photographs of locations in the United States.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 8 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1908-1974 (Box 1; 6 folders)
Series 2: Letters, 1912-1993 (Box 1; 40 folders)
Series 3: Personal Business Records, 1924-1994 (Box 1-2; 0.7 linear feet)
Series 4: Notes and Writings, 1902-1974 (Box 2; 8 folders)
Series 5: Art Work, 1904-1991 (Box 2-4, 6, OV 8; 2.2 linear feet)
Series 6: Scrapbooks, 1919-1973 (Box 4, 7; 0.9 linear feet)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1916-1995 (Box 5-6, OV 8; 1.0 linear feet)
Series 8: Photographs, 1924-1971 (Box 5-7, OV 8; 0.7 linear feet)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Clark, Herbert F.; Cornett, Robert G.; Rolle, A. H. O. (August H. O.), 1875-1940; Seaton, Charles; Society of Animal Artists; Washington Landscape Club
Subjects-Topical:
Artists--Washington (D.C.); Etchers--Washington (D.C.); Landscape painters--New York (State); Landscape painting--20th century--Washington (D.C.); Printmakers Washington (D.C.); Relief (Sculpture)
Subjects-Geographical:
New York (State)
Types of Materials:
Awards; Christmas cards; Drawings; Etchings; Paintings; Photographs; Poems; Prints; Travel sketches; Scrapbooks; Sketches
Names:
Berryman, Clifford Kennedy, 1869-1949; Bransom, Paul, 1885; Lowe, James Russell; Lyon, Rowland, 1904-; Sayre, Francis Bowes, 1885-1972
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1908-1974, Series 1:; (Box 1; 6 folders)
  Biographical material includes genealogical notes, biographical accounts, a baptismal record, marriage license, driver's license, membership cards, an award medal and ribbons, a death certificate, and address books.
  - Miscellaneous Biographical Material, 1908-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Award Medal and Ribbons, 1925-1960, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 2-5)
  - Address Books, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letters, 1912-1993, Series 2:; (Box 1; 40 folders)
  Letters are from friends and colleagues including Clifford K. Berryman, Paul Bransom, James Russell Lowe, Rowland Lyon, and Francis Bowes Sayre.
  - Letters from Correspondents with Surnames "A" - "C," undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters from Correspondents with Surnames "D" - "K," undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letters from Correspondents with Surnames "L," undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letters from Correspondents with Surnames "M," undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letters from Correspondents with Surnames "N" - "R," undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters from Correspondents with Surnames "S," undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Letters from Correspondents with Surnames "T" - "Z," undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letters, 1912-1919 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letters, 1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letters, 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Letters, 1927-1929 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letters, 1930-1939 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letters, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Letters, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Letters, 1946-1949 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Letters, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Letters, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Letters, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Letters, 1967, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
  - Letters, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Letters, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Letters, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Lettrs, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Letters, 1972, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 31-33)
  - Letters, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Letters, 1974, (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 35-38)
  - Letters, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Letters, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Letters, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Letters, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Letters, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Letters, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Letters, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Letters, 1983-1993 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Personal Business Records, 1924-1994, Series 3:; (Box 1-2; 0.7 linear feet)
  Personal business records include a deed for Moore's father's gallery, priced labels for art work, lists of art work, price lists, records of art work sold, bank account records, miscellaneous receipts, and a ledger concerning Moore's works left in trust after his death.
  - Copy of Patent for Moore's Design for an Artist's Kit, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Deed for Moore Galleries, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Priced Labels for Miscellaneous Art Work, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Priced Labels for Etchings, undated, (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 50-51)
  - Priced Labels for Hand-Colored Etchings, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Priced Labels for Hand-Colored Lithographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Priced Labels for Lithographs of Etchings, undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Priced Labels for Hand-Colored Lithographs of Etchings, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Priced Labels for Hand-Colored Lithographs of Paintings, undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Lists of Art Work and Price Lists, 1960-1981, undated, (13 folders) (Box 1, Folder 57-69)
  - Log Book of Lists of Art Work Given Away, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Log Book of Lists of Art Work and Art Work Sold, 1925-1936 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Log Book of Art Work Sold, 1938, 1966, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Bank Account Record Book, 1961-1967, 1974-1976, 1974-1986, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
  - Bank Account Record Book and List of Art Work, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bank Account Record Book, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bank Account Record, 1985-1988, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 8-10)
  - Receipts for Sale of Art Work, 1947-1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Receipts, 1952-1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Ledger Concerning Moore's Art Work Left in Trust, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Notes and Writings, 1902-1974, Series 4:; (Box 2; 8 folders)
  Notes and writings consist of nine poems by Moore, a log book of The Ramblers, lists of art work sold, lists of art work by others, and a funeral registry book listing mourners' names.
  - Poems, 1902, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
  - Log Book of The Ramblers, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Lists of Collectors and Art Work Sold, 1965-1971 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Lists of Art Work by Others, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Funeral Registry Book, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Notes and Writings, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
- Art Work, 1904-1991, Series 5:; (Box 2-4, 6, OV 8; 2.2 linear feet)
  Art work consists of 1040 drawings, 43 watercolor sketches, 526 etchings, 187 lithographs, 8 paintings, and 5 bas-relief sculptures. Subjects are primarily of wildlife and nature, landscapes, seascapes, urban scapes, and architecture. Portrait drawings and etchings by Moore include those of fellow artists Herbert F. Clark, Robert G. Cornett, August H. O. Rolle, and Charles Seaton. The bas-relief sculptures are of a lion, buffalo, fish, and penguin. Art work by others includes drawings and prints by Arthur Beaumont, Herbert F. Clark, Edwin G. Cassedy, J. C. Claghorn, John Doctoroff, Thomas Handforth, F. Dano Jackley, W. L. Maclean, Arvid Nyholm, Eliot O'Hara, Walter King Stone, and Ruel P. Tolman.
  A portion of the artwork is organized according to a numbering system of unknown origin, possible created by Moore.
  - Art Work Numbered BBM 51-64, 1917-1934 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Art Work Numbered BBMLP 001-844, 1921-1970, undated, (53 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 2, Folder 23-75)
  - Portrait Drawings and Drawings of Human Figures, 1904-1916 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Drawings of Animals, undated, (4 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 2-5)
  - Drawings of Birds, 1934-1936, undated, (7 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 6-12)
  - Drawings of Clouds, 1946-1967, undated, (10 folders) (Box 3, Folder 13-22)
  - Drawings of Shells, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Drawings of Plants, undated, (2 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
  - Drawings of Landscapes and Seascapes, undated, (9 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 26-34)
  - Drawing of a Cityscape, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Drawings of Views of Washington, D.C., 1931-1934, undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Watercolor Sketch of a Boy Fishing, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Watercolor Sketches of Animals and Birds, undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Watercolor Sketches of Landscapes and Seascapes, undated, (4 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 39-42)
  - Watercolor Sketches of Views of Washington, D.C., 1920-1921, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Portrait Etchings, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Etchings of Animals, undated, (5 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 45-49)
  - Etchings of Birds, undated, (8 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 50-57)
  - Etchings of Landscapes and Seascapes, undated, (3 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 58-60)
  - Etchings of Views of Washington, D. C., undated, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 61-62)
  - Etchings of Miscellaneous Buildings, undated, (2 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 63-64)
  - Commercial Lithographs of Animals and Birds, undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Lithograph Portrait of a Man, undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Lithographic Plate of a Landscape, undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Lithographs of Views of Washington, D.C., undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Lithograph and Lithographic Plate of George Washington Tavern in Bladensburg, Maryland, undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Lithographs of the Rotunda at University of Virginia, undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Paintings of Animals, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 71-72)
  - Paintings of Landscapes and a Town, undated, (2 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 3, Folder 73-74)
  - Relief Sculptures of Animals and Birds, undated (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Relief Sculptures of Animals and Birds, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Art Work by Others, 1910-1991, undated, (5 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6 and OV 8) (Box 4, Folder 3-7)
  - Oversized Drawing BBMLP 463 of Landscapes, undated, (from Box 2, Folder 44) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Drawing BBMLP 470 of Landscape, 1952, (from Box 2, Folder 45) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Drawing BBMLP 517of Landscape, undated, (from Box 2, Folder 49) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Drawing BBMLP 519 of Landscape, undated, (from Box 2, Folder 50) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Drawing BBMLP 572 of Landscape, 1958, (from Box 2, Folder 55) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Drawing BBMLP 676 of a Town and Team of Horses, undated, (from Box 2, Folder 62) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Drawing BBMLP 755 of Landscape, 1955, (from Box 2, Folder 65) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Drawing BBMLP 767 of Landscape, 1934, (from Box 2, Folder 69) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Drawing BBMLP 788 of Landscapes, undated, (from Box 2, Folder 71) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Six Oversized Drawings of Animals, undated, (from Box 3, Folder 5) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Four Oversized Drawings of Birds, undated, (from Box 3, Folder 12) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Two Oversized Drawings of Plants, undated, (from Box 3, Folder 25) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Six Oversized Drawings of Landscapes, undated, (from Box 3, Folder 34) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Two Oversized Drawings of Views of Washington, D.C., 1931, undated, (from Box 3, Folder 36) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - An Oversized Watercolor Sketch of a Bird, undated, (from Box 3, Folder 38) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Two Oversized Watercolor Sketches of Landscapes, undated, (from Box 3, Folder 42) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Two Oversized Etchings of Animals, undated, (from Box 3, Folder 49) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Two Oversized Etchings of Birds, undated, (from Box 3, Folder 50) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Five Oversized Etchings of Landscapes and Seascapes, undated, (from Box 3, Folder 60) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Two Oversized Etchings of Miscellaneous Buildings, undated, (from Box 3, Folder 64) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Nine Oversized Lithographs of Views of Washington, D.C. and Vicinity, undated, (from Box 3, Folder 68) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - An Oversized Oil Painting on Board of a Landscape, undated, (from Box 3, Folder 73) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - An Oversized Etching by J. Docking, a Lithograph by F. J. Frost, and an Etching by Bruff R. LeVan, undated, (from Box 4, Folder 5) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - An Oversized Lithograph Portrait of Herbert Hoover by John Doctoroff, undated, (from Box 4, Folder 5) (Box OV 8)
- Scrapbooks, 1919-1973, Series 6:; (Box 4, 7; 0.9 linear feet)
  Scrapbooks 1-7 primarily contain etchings, watercolor sketches, and scattered printed material and photographs of art work. Scrapbooks 8-12 contain clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, reproductions of art work, scattered letters, price lists, photographs of art work, a photograph of Moore, and the occasional original print.
  - Scrapbook 1, undated, (6 folders) (Box 4, Folder 8-13)
  - Scrapbook 2, undated, (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 14-16)
  - Scrapbook 3, undated, (4 folders) (Box 4, Folder 17-20)
  - Scrapbook 4, undated, (5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 21-25)
  - Scrapbook 5, undated, (4 folders) (Box 4, Folder 26-29)
  - Scrapbook 6, undated, (5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 30-34)
  - Scrapbook 7, undated, (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 35-37)
  - Scrapbook 9, 1919-1932 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Scrapbook 10, 1924-1971, (5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 39-43)
  - Scrapbook 11, 1959-1964, (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 44-46)
  - Scrapbook 12, 1963-1973, (8 folders) (Box 4, Folder 47-54)
  - Scrapbook 8, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Printed Material, 1916-1995, Series 7:; (Box 5-6, OV 8; 1.0 linear feet)
  Printed material consists of clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, a prospectus from the Society of Animal Artists, book Animals of American History illustrated by Paul Bransom, booklets concerning various printmakers, and reproductions of art work, including portraits of Herbert Hoover and Charles Curtis. Brochures concern art schools including the Hill School of Art, arts organizations including the Arts Club of Washington, the Miniature Painters, Sculptors, and Gravers Society, and the New York Graphic Society, and the sale of Moore's art work, and travel brochures for New York State.
  - Clippings, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Clippings of Images of Waterfowl, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
  - Clippings of Images of Trees, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - General Clippings, 1924-1994, (10 folders) (Box 5, Folder 6-15)
  - Prospectus from the Society of Animal Artists, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1928-1995, undated, (6 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 5, Folder 17-22)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Others, 1945, 1984-1987, undated, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 23-25)
  - Book Animals of American History Illustrated by Paul Bransom, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Booklet Charles Meryon by Frederick Heppel, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Booklet Concerning the Etchings of Mr. Whistler, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Booklet Dry-Points by Paul Helleu, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Booklet Ernest D. Roth by Herbert C. Pell, Jr., 1916 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Booklet Five Birds of Latin America by Lillian Cox Athey and Cover Illustration by Benson Bond Moore, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous Booklets, 1936-1995, undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Brochures for the Sale of Art Work by Moore, undated, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 33-35)
  - Brochures Concerning Art Schools, 1939-1967, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Brochures Concerning Arts Organizations, 1931, undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Travel Brochures for Mohonk, New York, 1929-1931 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Travel Brochures for Lake Minnewaska, New York, 1930, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous Brochures, 1993, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Art Supply Catalogs, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Reproductions of Art Work Depicting Animals, undated, (3 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 5, Folder 42-44)
  - Reproductions of Art Work Depicting Birds, undated, (3 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 5, Folder 45-47)
  - Reproductions of Art Work Depicting Landscapes, undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Reproductions of Art Work Depicting Seascapes, undated, (4 folders) (Box 5, Folder 49-52)
  - Reproductions of Art Work Depicting Views of Washington, D.C. and Vicinity, undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Reproductions of Art Work by Others, undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 6 and OV 8) (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - An Oversized Exhibition Announcement, undated, (from Box 5, Folder 17) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - An Oversized Booklet, undated, (from Box 5, Folder 32) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Three Oversized Reproductions of Art Work Depicting Animals, undated, (from Box 5, Folder 42) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Two Oversized Reproductions of Art Work Depicting Birds, undated, (from Box 5, Folder 46) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - An Oversized Reproduction of Art Work Depicting a Landscape, undated, (from Box 5, Folder 48) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Twenty-Two Oversized Reproductions of Art Work Depicting Views of Washington, D.C. and Vicinity, undated, (from Box 5, Folder 53) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Two Oversized Reproductions of Art Work by Others, undated, (from Box 5, Folder 54) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - An Oversized Map of Asia, undated, (from Box 5, Folder 55) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - An Oversized Map of the Society Islands, undated (Box OV 8)
- Photographs, 1924-1971, Series 8:; (Box 5-7, OV 8; 0.7 linear feet)
  Photographs are of Benson Bond Moore, his family, residence, colleagues including members of The Ramblers painting outdoors, and of art work. There are also travel photographs of Alabama, Florida (Miami), Georgia, Hawaii, Louisiana (New Orleans), North Carolina, Mississippi (Biloxi), Tennessee, Virginia, and Washington, D.C.
  - Photographs of Benson Bond Moore, 1958-1969, undated, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 56-58)
  - Photographs of Family Members, undated, (2 folders; Oversized Material Housed in OV 8) (Box 5, Folder 59-60)
  - Photographs of Friends and Colleagues, 1924-1971, undated, (7 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 6) (Box 5, Folder 61-67)
  - Photographs of Moore's Residence, 1958-1959, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 68-70)
  - Photographs of Travel in the United States, 1954, undated, (9 folders) (Box 5, Folder 71-79)